<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>English</title>
        <description>Articulate literary works by diligent students</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self"
        type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 23:58:49 +0530</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 23:58:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
        
        <item>
            <title>Photovoltaic Cell</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Photovoltaic Cell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photovoltaic’s (PV) covers the conversion of light into electricity using semiconducting materials that exhibit the photovoltaic effect, a phenomenon studied in physics, photochemistry, and electrochemistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical photovoltaic system employs solar panels, each comprising a number of solar cells, which generate electrical power. The first step is the photoelectric effect followed by an electrochemical process where crystallized atoms, ionized in a series, generate an electric current.PV Installations may be ground-mounted, rooftop mounted or wall mounted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solar PV generates no pollution. The direct conversion of sunlight to electricity occurs without any moving parts. Photovoltaic systems have been used for fifty years in specialized applications, standalone and grid-connected PV systems have been in use for more than twenty years. They were first mass-produced in 2000, when German environmentalists and the Eurosolar organization got government funding for a ten thousand roof program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-link&quot;&gt;Download Link:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/phcell12390&quot;&gt;Photovoltaic Cell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;---mayankjbhalerao&quot;&gt;-  Mayank.J.Bhalerao&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/phcell.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/phcell.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Hyperloop High Speed Transportation System</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hyperloop High Speed Transportation System&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Train is one of the important transport in the whole world. Day by day train transportation becoming more comfortable according to time requirement, which is basically depends upon the speed. In a Normal vehicle the transportation system is moving in free atmosphere, so there is obstacle of air flowing in the atmosphere to the transport systems ,as a  result the speed of the vehicle get decreased. But in Hyperloop transport free air is not the obstacle because the train is moving in a tube. It is being developed as an open source project. Hyperloop is the concept for very high-speed, fixed guide way surface transportation. Hyperloop consist of a low pressure tube with capsule that are transported at both low and high speeds throughout the length of the tube.  High speed Hyperloop train accelerates to 100 mph in 4 seconds in first test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-link&quot;&gt;Download Link:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/hpp12390&quot;&gt;Hyperloop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;---gayatri-mohan-mankar-kartik-gopal-shilwant&quot;&gt;-  Gayatri Mohan Mankar, Kartik Gopal Shilwant&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/hyperloop2.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/hyperloop2.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Hyperloop Transportation System</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Hyperloop Transportation System&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conventional modes of transportation of people consists of four unique types and that are rail, road, water, and air. These modes of transport tend to be either relatively slow, expensive or a combination of both. Hyperloop is a new mode of transport that seeks to change this pattern by being both fast and inexpensive for people and goods. Hyperloop is a proposed mode of passenger and freight transportation that propels a capsule-like vehicle through a near-vacuum tube at more than airline speed. The pods would accelerate to cruising speed gradually using a linear electric motor and glide above their track using passive magnetic levitation or air bearings. Hyperloop consists of a low pressure tube with capsules that are transported at both low and high speeds throughout the length of the tube. The capsules are supported on a cushion of air, featuring pressurized air and aerodynamic lift. Passengers may enter and exit Hyperloop at stations located either at the ends of the tube, or branches along the tube length. It quickly becomes apparent just how dramatically the Hyperloop could change transportation, road congestion and minimize the carbon footprint globally. With the Hyperloop, extremely fast, inexpensive intercity travel would be widely accessible. If both people and goods can move more quickly and comparatively cheaply, rapid growth is a logical outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-link&quot;&gt;Download Link:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/hyperloop12390&quot;&gt;Hyperloop Transportation System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;--omkar-govind--karlekar-akshay-shashikant-ghule&quot;&gt;- Omkar Govind  Karlekar, Akshay Shashikant Ghule&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&quot;dme&quot;&gt;DME&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/hyperloop1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/hyperloop1.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Geothermal Energy</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Geothermal Energy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The search and utilization of geothermal energy commenced in Italy in nearly 1900s. Today, Italy produce sufficient power from geothermal energy to operate its entire network of electrical railroads. Geothermal power plants use hydrothermal resources which have two common ingredients water (hydro) and heat (thermal). Geothermal plants require high temperature (300 to 700 degrees Fahrenheit) hydrothermal resources that may come from either dry steam wells or hot water wells. We can use these resources by drilling wells into the earth and piping the steam or hot water to the surface. Geothermal wells are one to two miles deep. Geothermal energy is a renewable resource.   One of its biggest advantages is that it is constantly available.  The constant flow of heat from the Earth ensures an inexhaustible and essentially limitless supply of energy for billions of years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-link&quot;&gt;Download Link:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/geoth12390&quot;&gt;Geothermal Energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;----patil-amit-rajesh-patil-sattyam-sudesh&quot;&gt;-   Patil Amit Rajesh, Patil Sattyam Sudesh&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/geothermal.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/geothermal.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>E-Waste Management &amp; Recycling</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;E-Waste Management &amp;amp; Recycling&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s modern era, it has become necessary for everyone to be familiar with the gadgets like computer, mobile phones. At the same time, tremendous growth in such devices and gadgets faster change of technology and frequent innovations in ICT sector, had left the world with a threat of deterioration in environmental conditions and human health as the-waste of electronic and electrical equipment, which contains hazardous components, is still handled in an environmentally unfriendly manner mainly in developing nations. It is huge challenge for
the nations to handle e-waste in responsible manner and protect the environment. So there should be an effective management and recycling system for handling e-waste in a proper technical manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-link&quot;&gt;Download Link:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/ewaste12390&quot;&gt;E-Waste Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;----v-n--karkaria--s-r-solanke&quot;&gt;-   V. N.  Karkaria,  S. R. Solanke&lt;/h6&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/ewaste.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/ewaste.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Hybrid Electric Car</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Hybrid Electric Car&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a days petrol, CNG or Diesel cars are causing a humongous problem by emitting polluted gases and polluting our Earth. They also are using the crude oil reserves that our planet has got and because of this reason one day can come where there will be no drop of crude oil underneath our surface. The simple solution for this is Hybrid Electric car. Hybrid Electric car is an automobile which works on electricity and it can generate electricity by renewable energy resources. The electric motor creates an efficiency of 95% which is too high in comparison to conventional motor engine which can create an efficiency of 35%. So Hybrid electric car can make our Earth pollution free as major reason to pollution on Earth is due to automobile and hence we are going to present about how an Hybrid electric car is constructed, how it works and many other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-link&quot;&gt;Download Link:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/ecar12390&quot;&gt;Hybrid Electric Car&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;---vispi-nevile-karkaria-saurabh-ramesh-solanke&quot;&gt;-  Vispi Nevile Karkaria, Saurabh Ramesh Solanke&lt;/h6&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/ecar.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/ecar.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Multi-Cylinder Ball Milling Machine</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Multi-Cylinder Ball Milling Machine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electrode material has to be crushed into smaller particles and that can be mostly done by ball milling machines. This grinding is done by conventional ball milling machine, jet ball milling machine, planetary ball milling machine and various other machines. But, these machines are expensive and they consume lot of power. Also swelling of electrode material also takes place in conventional ball milling machine. A ball milling machine named Forward Reverse motion, Multi-cylinder ball milling machine has been proposed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this ball milling machine there are four cylinder so that more than one samples can 
be milled at a time and a new type of motion has been achieved. This motion is forward reverse motion that gives better results in comparison to conventional ball milling machine and that also in cheap cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;download-link&quot;&gt;Download Link:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/ballmill12390&quot;&gt;Ball Mill Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;----v-n--karkaria--s-r-solanke-p-r-korgaonkar-m-j-bhalerao&quot;&gt;-   V. N.  Karkaria,  S. R. Solanke, P. R. Korgaonkar, M. J. Bhalerao,&lt;/h6&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/ballmill.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/20/ballmill.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
